Guide to the George Pólya Papers SC0337
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-1989-132
  - Class Materials, Subseries 3
    - Miscellaneous notes - Psyc. 262, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Probability, Statistics - Math. 123, 125, 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - Calculus of Probability - Math. 123, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
    - Probability and Statistics - Math. 123, 125, 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Calculus of Variations - Seminar, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Group Theory with Applications, 1938-1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Potential Theory, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Differential Geometry, 1941-1959 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
    - Introduction to Elementry and Analytic Number Theory, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Introduction to Elementry and Analytic Number Theory, 1941-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Minimum Principle Approximations, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Minimum Principle Approximations, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Algebra and Number Theory, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Singularities of Power Series, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Vectors, 1935-1948 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Integral Equations, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Smith College, Mathematics 35B, 36B, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Introduction to Combinatorics - CS150, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Mathematics 5 (Berkeley), 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Aspects of Calculus, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - Mathematics 111s, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Combinatorial Theory, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Introduction to Combinatorics - CS150, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Pólya Miscellaneous Classes, 1958-196? (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - E.T. Jaynes, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Elementary Mathematics From Higher Point of View - Math 129 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - How To Solve The Problem - Math 129, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Lattice Points - Math Seminar, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Manuscripts, Subseries 4
    - Essays On Mathematical Method, Discovery, and Teaching, undated (Box 4, Folder 14-17)
    - Essays On Mathematical Method, Discovery, and Teaching (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Drafts and notes for Essays On Mathematical Method, Discovery, and Teaching, ~1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mathematics and Plausible Reasoning - Appendix, 1955-1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mathematics and Plausible Reasoning - Illustrations, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mathematical Discovery, undated (Box 5, Folder 6-12)
    - Mathematical Discovery, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Corrections for Mathematical Discovery, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Complex Variables, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
    - Mathematical Methods in Science, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Notebook 1, Aufgaben und lehrsatze, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Notebook 2, Aufgaben und lehrsatze, undated (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - Aufgaben und Lehrsatze - Addenda, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Aufgaben und Lehrsatze, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - IX: Psychologie, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - III: Auffassung, Einfall, Ansatz, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - V: typische Anschlusse von Hilfsaufgaben, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - VI: Schetzung der Aussichten, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - VII: Die Phasen der Untersuchung, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - VII: Die Phasen der Untersuchung, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Notes for a book, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mathematical Discovery in the Classroom (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Notes, 1949-1954 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Notes for a Book, ~1941 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Rules and Moves (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Essential Texts in German How To Solve It, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Figures and Drawing (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Bound Notebook, 1957-1977 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Notes from previous bound notebook (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Problems (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Talks, 1940-1946 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Teaching Mathematics, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Notes for Short Papers - Problems, 1971-1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - How To Solve It - Symposium, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Rules of Thumb, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Seattle for Oldsters, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - San Diego, June, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Galileo, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Slides, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Talks: Seattle, San Diego, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Daylight Arc, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Symmetry of Ornaments, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Slides for a talk, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Films, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Lectures on Travels, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Notebook (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Notebook, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Mathematical Education, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Unfinished and Planned Writing, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Fragments of Writings, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Henryk Lauer, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Misc. Pólya Manuscripts, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Lecture Notes, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Various Lectures, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Summer Institute Lecture, 1972-1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Numerical Integration, 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Lectures - Plausible Reasoning, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Pólya Counting Method, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - George Pólya Article for Szego's Collected Papers, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Calculus of Probabilities (French), undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Papers by Pólya, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Project Hilgard, ~1953 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Research Materials, Subseries 5
    - Experimental Tables, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "The Heuristic of George Pólya and its Relation to Artificial Intelligence", by Allen Newell, Feb. 1981, draft, 50pp, plus Pólya’s letters of thanks to Newell (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Research Notes, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
    - Solow, Daniel, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Problems, 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 15-16)
    - Miscellaneous Problems Collected from Various Sources, 1954-1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Primes (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Notebook for Mathematical Discovery, 1953-1977 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
    - Notebook: Heuristic Logic (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Odlyzko - Zeros of Zeta Function, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Michael Klass, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Rubik's Cube, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Generalizing Hardy's Theorem, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Problems, 1933-1939 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Stochastic Proceses - Feller (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Infinite Series and Fourier Series, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Pointsets and Real Functions (Punktmengen und reale Funktionen), undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Positions of Zeros, 1929-1937 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Schur Darstelungstheorie, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Entire Series Satisfying Algebraic Differential Equations, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Problems, 1956-1985 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Pinboards and Geoboards, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - 117A and Ingham, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Polyhedra and Other Enumerations, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - Miscellaneous Notes on Problems, 1972-1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Inequalities involving integrals of functions and their derivatives," by Donald Benson, 23pp (mimeograph), 1966 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Our Aim is to Find an Approximation to n!" (typed paper, unknown author and date), undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "The basic concepts of Pólya’s theory of enumeration, with examples from the structural classification of mechanisms," by F. Freudenstein, 26pp (typescript), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Variational Properties of Steady Fall in Stokes Flow", by H.F. Weinberger, 51pp (typescript), undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Williamson, S.G., undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Combination Problems Involving Points and Lines in a Plane, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "Modern Heuristic in Historical Perspective With Implications for Research Pedagogy," by Elton Carter and Robert Richey, in General Semantics Bulletin (offprint), 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Pascal Letters, by Renyi (Manuscript of the Hungarian version of the Letters on Probability by Alfred Renyi), undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Martin Gardner Problem, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "The Problem of Packing a Number of Equal Nonoverlapping Circles on a Sphere," by H.S.M. Coxeter, in Transactions of the New York Academy of Sciences (reprint), with notes by Pólya, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Example Generation," by Edwina Rissland, Computer and Information Science Technical Report 80-14, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "On the Art of Problem Solving," by Murray S. Klamkin, Scientific Laboratory, Ford Motor Co., 41pp (publication preprint), plus graph by Pólya, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "Transfinite Diameter and Analytic Continuation of Functions of Two Complex Variables", by M. Schiffer and J. Siciak, Tech. Rep. No. 1100, Applied Mathematics and Statistics Lab, Stanford, plus three pages of notes, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "On Pólya Frequency Functions IV: The Fundamental Spline Functions and Their Limits", by H.B. Curry and I.J. Schoenberg, in Journal D’Analyse Mathematique, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Handbook for Planning an Effective Mathematics Program, California State Department of Education, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Radius of Circumscribed Sphere, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Pal Turan and George Alexits death notices from Hungarian Academy of Sciences, 1976, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - "Counting of Isomeric Hydrocarbons with Asymptotic Results," by Joel G.W. Rogers, 26pp. (manuscript), 1971 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Reprints and Articles, Subseries 6
    - Bib. #163: Heuristic reasoning and the theory of probability, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Bib. #168: Approximations to the area of the ellipsoid, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Bib. #172: A minimum problem about the motion of a solid through a fluid, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Bib. #174: On patterns of plausible inference, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Bib. #195, 196, 199: Two Notes on Minimum Principle Approximations, Techical report No. 29, Stanford, 1953; Estimates for Eigenvalues, Page Proofs, 1954, 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Bib. #200: More isoperimetric inequalities proved and conjectured, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bib. #202, 203, 206: On the Characteristic Frequencies of a Symmetric Membrane, 15pp, Tech. Rep. No 40, Stanford, 1955 (2 copies); On the Ratio of Consecutive Eigenvalues, 21pp (with L.E. Payne and H.F. Weinberger), Tec. Rep. No 41, Stanford, 1955; The Mathematics Teacher, LII/1, 1959: Mathematics as a Subject for Learning Plausible Reasoning (translation), 1955-1959 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Bib. #209: Remarks on De La Vallee-Poussin Means and Convex Conformal Maps of the Circle, 76pp, Tech. Rep. No 70, Stanford (with I.J. Schoenberg), 1957 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Bib. #215, 219, 217: On the Eigenvalues of Vibrating Membranes; Two More Inequalities Between Physical and Geometrical Quantities -- Tech. Rep. No 88, Stanford, 1960; Archimedes (magazine), 1960, containing: Die Mathematische Erziehung (p.. 103) and Die Mathematikals Schule der plausiblen Schliessens (page proof, in back of magazine; The Mathematics Teacher (magazine), 1961, containing: The Minimum Fraction of Popular Vote that Can Elect the President of the United States, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Bib. #222: Intuitive outline of the solution of a basic combinatorial problem, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Bib. #232, 236, 241, 249: Entiers Algebriques ... (1969); Two Incidents (1970); Stanford Competitive Exam (1973); On the Zeros ... (1976), 1969-1976 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Bib. #233: Some mathematicians I have known, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Bib. #234: On the isoperimetric theorem: History and strategy, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Bib. #235: Gaussian binomial coefficients and the enumeration of inversions, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Bib. #237: Gaussian Binomial Coefficients (with G.L. Alexanderson), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Bib. #238: Methodology or Heuristics, Strategy or Tactics?, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Bib. #239: Eine Erinnerung un Hermann Weyl, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Bib. #240: A letter by Professor Pólya, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Bib. #242: A story with a moral, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Bib. #243: Formation, not only Information, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Bib. #244: As I read them, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Bib. #245: Partition of a finite set into structured subsets, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Bib. #246: Probabilities in Proof-Reading, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Bib. #247: Guessing and Proving, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Bib. #248: As their students see them, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Bib. #250: A note of welcome, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Bib. #251: More on Guessing and Proving, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Norsk Matematisk Tidsskrift, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - California Mathematics Council Bulletin, 1954-1958 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Mathematical Log, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Generalization, Specialization, Analogy, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Dedication of Stanford University Computation Center, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Die Heuristik and Conference Procedings, 1964-1966 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Sylvania Competitive Examination, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Articles by Pólya, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Some Articles by Pólya, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Book: The 1953 Jennings Scholar Lectures, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Book: Inequalities: Theory of Majorization and Its Applications, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Book: Research Papers in Statistics, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Book: Do You Teach? Views on College Teaching, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Book: A Taste of Science, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Pólya's Theory of Counting, 1959-1965 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Articles about Pólya, 1963-1988 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Articles and Journals related to Pólya, 1966-1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Journals related to Pólya, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "An Elementary Solution of Pólya's Orchard Problems," by Tracy Allen, 16pp (typescript), 1983 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "Omzien in bewondering," by N.G. de Bruijn, pamphlet, 18pp, retirement speach in Dutch (references to Pólya), 1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "II: Drunkard's Walk on an Infinite Lattice", by Peter Doyle, pp. 34-73 (typescript), 1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "A Method for Technological Predictions", by D.G. Ellson, 20pp (typescript), plus letter from Ellson comparing his paper to "Patterns of Plausible Inference", 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Two AI papers by Friedman (on Plausible Inference), typescript, with Pólya letter (presumably unsent), 1980 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - David Hawkins publications, 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "The Ancient Tradition of Geometric Problems", Part I, Section 7: Apollonius, by Wilbur Knorr, 65pp (typescript), with note by Pólya, manuscript, crossed out, on back of letter, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Imre Lakatos e la 'filosofia della scoperta,'" by Genner Luigi Linguiti, Lucea, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "What Every Secondary School Mathematics should Read" (references Pólya books), by Lowell Leake, Mathematics Teacher, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, Subseries 7
    - Stanford University Mathematics Examination, 1946-1965 (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
    - Committee on the Teaching of Undergraduate Mathematics, 1976-1979 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous articles, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Choice [Combinatorial Analysis], undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Eckford Cohen, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Bruno de Finetti, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - P. Cartier and D. Hejhal, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Ernst Mohr, 1962-1983 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - S.C. Bhatnagar, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Colin Thompson, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - John Brillhart, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Jean Pedersen, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Imre Lakatos, 1971-1978 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Antoine Ehrhard, ~1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Latta - Complex Variables, 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Paul Halmos, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Feldzamen, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Polyhedra - Federico, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Ars Expositionis: Euler as Writer and Teacher [typescript of paper by Gerald L. Alexanderson], 1982 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Fejer Lipot, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - John Ryff (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Arne Baartz, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Albert Einstein, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Stella Pólya, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Shiffman, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - School Mathematics Project, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Hungarian Newspaper Clippings, 1971, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Pólya and Wehl, 1918 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Hilbert to Hurwitz, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Herzberger, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Pieces of Paper, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - "Identification and Development of the Mathematically Talented - The Hungarian Experience," Agnes Arvai Wieschenberg Dissertation, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Alvin White, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Items, 1911-1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Certificate, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Honorary Ph.D., Univ. of Waterloo; photo (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - School Records (Hungarian/European), 1888-1914 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Assorted Awards, 1920-1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Professional Associations, 1950-1977 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Poster about lectures by Pólya, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Slides for a Talk (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Chessboard Thank You (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Honorary Membership, Santa Clara Valley Mathematics Association, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Santa Clara Valley Mathematics Association Life Member Plaque, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Slides (graphs, diagrams, etc.), undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Photograph Album, 1917-1978 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Includes other mathematicians and scientists, congresses and meetings, family images, and others; images are well labelled.
    - Copy prints of images from Photograph Album (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - School Papers, 1887-1905 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Research note cards (mostly in German) (Box 21)
  - Restricted Materials, Subseries 8
    - Class roll books, 1960-1963 (Box 20)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2003-185
  - Miscellaneous Mathematical Notes (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tributes to George Pólya, 1957-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
  - Reminisces of Gorge Pólya, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Articles on Mathematics and Science (in English, German), 1933-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Time Magazine article on post-Kennedy assassination, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Articles on Lee and Grace Lorch, 1957-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mathematical papers by Pólya (in English, French), 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Articles and obituaries of mathematicians (in English, French, German), 1938-1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Student Examinations (Blue Books), undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Notes in preparation for Pólya’s book with Gábor Szego, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Mathematical papers (in German), 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Speech to the International Congress of Mathematicians, Bologna, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Summer Mathematical Conferences, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Trip to Zurich, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - National Lecture Tour, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
  - Resumes of Pólya, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Trinity College, Cambridge, England, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Pólya’s speeches (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Book Reviews, "Problems and Theorems in Analysis", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Book Reviews, "Mathematical Discovery: On Understanding Learning and Teaching Problem Solving" 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Book Reviews, "How to Solve It", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Book Reviews, "The Stanford Mathematics Problem Book", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Book Reviews, "Notes on Introductory Combinatories", 1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Book Reviews, "Isometric Inequalities in Mathematics", 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Book Reviews, "Patterns of Plausible Inference", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Book Reviews, "Mathematics and Plausible Reasoning", 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Secretary of Defense William Perry, student of Pólya, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Pamphlet "How to Teach Guessing", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Pólya Exhibit and Speech, Stanford, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Pólya’s notes "On Plausible Reasoning", undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letters to Pólya, 1941-1995 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Papers on Mathematics, 1941-1975 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1991 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Papers on Pólya Family History (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Pamphlet, "The Four Color Theorem", 1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - The University of Tasmania, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 48-49)
  - Correspondence with Gerald Alexanderson, Santa Clara University, 1972-1997 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Summer Institute for Teachers of Collegiate Mathematics at Stanford, General File, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Summer Institute for Teachers of Collegiate Mathematics at Stanford, Professor Schoenburg, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 52-54)
  - Summer Institute for Teachers of Collegiate Mathematics at Stanford, Professor Allendoerfer, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Summer Institute for Teachers of Collegiate Mathematics at Stanford, Professor Lehmer, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Manuscript on Probabilities (in French) undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Letters from Issai Schur and Carl Ludwig Siegel (in German), 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Papers for Pólya’s "Groups, Graphs and Chemical Compounds" (in German), 1930 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Paper "Zweck und Hillel" (in German), undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Paper "Das Schliemen" (in German), undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Papers in German and French, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Manuscript of JLWV Jensen (in Danish), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Papers and correspondence on Pólya’s Collected Works (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - List of Dissertations, 1914-1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1953-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1943-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8-19)
  - Figures for "Mathematics and Plausible Reasoning", undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Papers from Institute Henri Poincaré, Paris (in French), undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Papers on Robert Weber, Stella Pólya’s father, 1850-1915 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence with Swiss educators on problem solving (in German, French), 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Physical problems often involving differential equations (in German), undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Notes on "finite" Fourier integrals, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Postcards from Edmund Landau (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Examinations, Stanford, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Papers from the Swiss Institute of Technology, Zurich, 1924-1940 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
  - Mathematical Association of America lectures, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Stanford Mathematics Fellowship Program, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 32)